Guide to the Virtual Library of Virginia records, 1994-2004
George Mason University Libraries
- Series 1: Committees, April 1994-September 2004; (13 boxes)
  - Subseries 1.1: VIVA Steering Committee Meetings, July 1994-June 2002
    - Steering Committee Meeting, December 2-3, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 6)
      Agendas and notes from the October meeting at University of Virginia in Charlottesville. Also included is a Users Committee report, Interlibrary loan report, VIVA pamphlet rough draft, VIVA Preliminary Assessment Report and budget information.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, March 9-10, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 7)
      Agendas, action items, correspondence and notes from the March meeting at George Mason University in Fairfax. Also included is a definition of associate membership, Encoded Archival Description conversion guidelines, interlibrary loan guidelines and librarian lists.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, June 8-9, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 8)
      Agendas, correspondence and notes from the June meeting at James Madison University in Harrisonburg. Also included are member and committee lists, periodical access article, presentation slides about collection and access, budget information, and a users committee report.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, August 8, 2000 (Box 6, Folder 9)
      Agendas, correspondence, retreat summary and notes from the August retreat at Virginia Tech in Blacksburg. Also included are member lists, VIVA preliminary assessment, budget information and lending information.
    - VIVA Assessment, 1999-2000 (Box 7, Folder 1)
      Preliminary assessment reports for VIVA. Reports include general initial observations about the overall effectiveness of VIVA. Assessment of the effectiveness of the administrative structure of VIVA; review of the documented financial benefits realized by the VIVA program; assessment of VIVA's effectiveness in meetings; recommendations provided. Also included are planning documents for the assessment.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, September 14-15, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 2)
      Agendas, minutes and notes from the September meeting at Old Dominion University in Norfolk. Also included is budget information, outreach committee report, budget information, and an Academic Libraries Survey.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, November 30-December 1, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
      Agendas, correspondence, minutes and notes from the November meeting at Mary Washington College in Fredericksburg. Also included is budget information, a New York Times article and a users committee report.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, March 8-9, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 4)
      Agendas, correspondence, notes, action items and minutes from the March meeting at Washington and Lee University in Lexington. Also included is a committee list, budget information and consortia article,
    - Steering Committee Meeting, June 7-8, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 5)
      Agendas, notes and minutes from the June meeting at Richard Bland College in Petersburg. Also included is budget information, nelinet summary of electronic resources in Massachusetts, Virginia Libraries article, presentation slides and an outreach committee report.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, July 23-24, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 6)
      Agendas and correspondence from the annual retreat at Randolph-Macon College in Ashland. Also included is organizational information, committee lists, participant institution lists, VIVA timeline, goals and objective lists and budget information.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, September 6, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 7)
      Agendas, notes and correspondence from the September meeting at Mary Baldwin College in Staunton. Also included is the Virginia Virtual University Draft Proposal, VIVA fact sheet, committee lists, State Council of Higher Education for Virginia press release and a VIVA organizational chart.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, December 6, 2001 (Box 7, Folder 8)
      Agendas, correspondence and notes from the Northern Virginia Community College in Manassas. Also included is an outreach committee report, budget information, committee list and subscription information.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, March 7, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 9)
      Agendas, correspondence and notes from the March meeting at Virginia Military Institute in Lexington. Also included is budget information and resource sharing committee report.
    - Steering Committee Meeting, June 6, 2002 (Box 7, Folder 10)
      Agendas, correspondence and notes from the June meeting at Christopher Newport University in Newport News. Also included is a Virginia Libraries article about the Virginia Heritage project, committee lists, presentation slides about committees, resources for users committee report and information about the Online Archive of California.
  - Subseries 1.2: VIVA Resource Users Committee, July 1994-September 2004
    This subseries contains material generated by the Resources for Users committee and its predecessors. Around 1999, the number of committees in VIVA was reduced drastically and committees were folded into others. The Resources for Users Committee began as the Electronic Collections Committee, was renamed the Collections Committee, then finally became the Resources for Users Committee. Documents in the subseries include information about Legi-Slate, budget information, journal scription information, meeting agendas, notes, and minutes, correspondence, committee lists, "Selection and Presentation of Commercially Available Electronic Resources: Issues and Practices" by Timothy D. Jewell, Cost Savings and Value Added Survey information, documents from regional meetings, VIVA workshops, a cataloging workshop and a collections development workshop, FirstSearch information, lists of institutional participants, budget information, contact directories, information from training fairs, information about Project Confidence and VIVA information packets.
    - VIVA: Collections Committee Communications. Etc., September 1994-June 2004 (Box 8, Folder 1)
      Collections committee correspondence and information including a list of participating institutions, a contact directory, a VIVA meeting schedule, and member lists from the following committees: Collections, Interlibrary Loan Enhancements, Special Collections, Technical Issues, User Services, Electronic Collections, Steering Committee, Resource Sharing, Resources for Users, Outreach, State Council of Higher Education Library Advisory.
    - VIVA-Collections Committee I, December 1995-January 1997 (Box 8, Folder 2)
      Information and correspondence from the Collections Committee including an article from the Cyber Librarian, online dictionary directories, budget information, FirstSearch information, committee member lists, also included is meeting information such as minutes, agendas, correspondence and notes.
    - VIVA-Collections Committee II, August-November 1994 (Box 8, Folder 3)
      Information and correspondence from the Collections Committee including a list of participating institutions, pricing proposals, budget information, a cost savings and value added 1996/1997 executive summary and institutional comments, and cost savings value added surveys.
    - User Services Regional Meeting, April 1995 (Box 8, Folder 4)
      Material generated by the User Services regional meeting held on April 4-7, 1995 at institutions throughout Virginia. Included are agendas, attendance lists, evaluation forms, brochure draft, and contact lists.
    - User Services Committee, August 1994-June 1997 (Box 8, Folder 5)
      Information and correspondence generated by the User Services committee material includes workshop organization guide, meeting agendas, minutes and notes, user services survey, FirstSearch user institutions, achievement list of user services committee, FirstSearch reference guide, Solinet information and an African American Poetry collection advertisement.
    - User Services Workshop, March-May 1997 (Box 8, Folder 6)
      Correspondence about the May 1997 VIVA workshop, also included is a registration confirmation.
    - User Services-Users Group, September 1997-November 1997 (Box 8, Folder 7)
      Information and correspondence generated by the User Services committee. Material includes the 1997 VLA/DCLA Conference agenda, VIVA list serve and FirstSearch information, meeting agendas and notes as well as User Group comments.
    - User Services-Cataloging Workshop, April 1998-April 1999 (Box 8, Folder 8)
      Information and correspondence about the May 1999 VIVA Cataloging Workshop. Materials include agendas, electronic cataloging guidelines, meeting notes, workshop outlines and workshop logistics.
    - User Services Collection Development Workshop, November 1997-March 1998 (Box 8, Folder 9)
      Information and correspondence about the March 1998 VIVA Users Services Collection Development Workshop. Materials include agendas, registration information, committee member lists, notes and report from the workshop.
    - Resources for Users Committee I, November 1994-July 1995 (Box 8, Folder 10)
      Information and correspondence from the Resources for Users committee. Materials include budget information, committee member lists, FirstSearch subscription information, meeting agendas, minutes and notes, Legi-Slate comparisons to Lexis Nexis, a press release, and request for proposal drafts.
    - Resources for Users Committee II, September 1994-December 1994 (Box 8, Folder 11)
      Information and correspondence from the Resources for Users committee. Materials include Internet Journal Services advertisements, meeting minutes and agendas, budget information, subscription information and requests for proposals.
    - Resources for Users Committee III, July 1994-November 1995 (Box 9, Folder 1)
      Information and correspondence from the Resources for Users committee. Materials include a list of goals for the committee, meeting notes, agendas and minutes, committee lists, subscription proposals, vendor lists, enrollment figures, electronic resource selection information and database information.
    - Resources for Users Committee, July 2001 (Box 9, Folder 2)
      "Selection and Presentation of Commercially Available Electronic Resources: Issues and Practices" by Timothy D. Jewell.
    - RUC-Cost Savings and Value Added Survey Final Report, 1995-1996 (Box 9, Folder 3)
      Two copies of the Executive Summary of a Cost Savings and Value Added Survey from 1995-1996
    - RUC-Cost Savings and Value Added Survey, 1996-1997 (Box 9, Folder 4)
      Documents generated by the Cost Savings and Value Added Survey 1995-1996, including executive summaries, correspondence, blank surveys, lists of available journals from IAC, Ideal (Academic Press) and Project Muse.
    - Resources for Users Committee, March 1997-October 1997 (Box 9, Folder 5)
      Information and correspondence from the Resources for Users committee. Materials include meeting notes, agendas, and minutes, budget info, newspaper and journal subscription info, journal articles and information about electronic collections.
    - RUC Training Fair, January 2000-March 2000 (Box 9, Folder 6)
      Information and correspondence from the March 2000 VIVA training fair. Materials include training information, meeting plans/schedules, meeting notes and agendas, registration information, VIVA publications, attendees lists, VIVA information packet and FirstSearch information.
    - RUC InfoTrac Training, August 2000 (Box 9, Folder 7)
      Information and correspondence about VIVA InfoTrac training workshops. Materials include registration and attendance information, workshop agendas and evaluation forms.
    - RUC Vendor Presentations, June 1999 (Box 9, Folder 8)
      Two VIVA information packets for vendor presentations. Packets include an agenda, evaluation, travel reimbursement information and VIVA fact sheet.
    - Resources for Users Committee, March 1998-June 1999 (Box 9, Folder 9)
      Information and correspondence from the Resources for Users committee. Materials include budget tables, meeting agendas, notes, and minutes, periodical information, cost surveys, budget information and Cost Saved and Value Added survey summary.
    - RUC - OVID Training Fair, August-November 1999 (Box 9, Folder 10)
      Information and correspondence from the August-September 1999 Resources for Users committee OVID Training Fair. Materials include registration and attendance lists, meeting schedules, agendas, evaluation forms, travel reimbursement information and thank-you letters.
    - Resources for Users Committee, January 1998-February 1999 (Box 10, Folder 1)
      Information and correspondence from the Resources for Users committee. Materials include meeting agendas, minutes, and notes, budgets information, database/journal subscription information, VIVA Collection Development Principles and Selection Criteria, a press release and Cost Saved and Value Added survey summary.
    - CIA net library -UVA, February-April 2000 (Box 10, Folder 2)
      Correspondence about the minutes from the February 2000 meeting of the VIVA Task Force on Cataloging and Intellectual Access. Material includes meeting minutes and an email.
    - CIA Workshop, Electronic Journals, from Aggregator Sources, October 1999-January 2000 (Box 10, Folder 3)
      Information and correspondence from the User Services Committee Subcommittee on Cataloging and Intellectual Access. Material includes meeting agendas notes, evaluation forms, presentation about creating web lists of electronic journals and a VIVA information packet including a VIVA pamphlet, fact sheet, communication information and presentation slides.
    - Cataloging, August 1996-October 1998 (Box 10, Folder 4)
      Information and correspondence from the User Services Committee Subcommittee on Cataloging and Intellectual Access. Material includes information on electronic journals, a report on electronic resources, meeting agendas and minutes, a "Report and Recommendations for Providing Intellectual Access to VIVA Resources" and cataloging guidelines.
    - Cataloging and Intellectual Access Task Force, August 1996-November 2001 (Box 10, Folder 5)
      Information and correspondence from the User Services Committee Subcommittee on Cataloging and Intellectual Access. Material includes meeting agendas, notes and minutes, information about SerialsSolutions and cataloging guidelines.
    - Project Confidence, January-April 1997 (Box 10, Folder 6)
      Information and correspondence from the Collections Committee's "Project Confidence", which was designed to let VIVA member institutions see stability and to encourage them to cancel print subscriptions to journals. Material includes lists of available journals, project reports, Academic Search FullTEXT 1,000 Database coverage lists, lists of available journals, a report of an overview of OhioLink's comparison of general "full text" journal article databases, a Proquest directory, lists of "Core Titles" for Project Confidence, meeting minutes and agendas, ARIEL instructions, a news release about publishers offering journals electronically, VIVA participation spreadsheet and an EBSCO information packet.
    - RFP Committee Vendor Presentations, March 1998 (Box 10, Folder 7)
      A description of a vendor presentation meeting in March of 1998 at the University of Richmond. Material includes a schedule of presentations and an evaluation form. Also included is a VIVA information folder which contains help advice for electronic collection vendors, meeting agenda and notes, a list of restaurants in University of Richmond vicinity, a draft of VIVA principles and selection criteria, VIVA listserv and home page information, a VIVA pamphlet, travel reimbursement information and committee lists.
    - RFP 1999 Vendor Presentation, April-August 1999 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Information and correspondence from the Request for Proposal committee. The request was for a database provider for abstracting and indexing services. Material includes an agendas for the RPF vendor presentations, registrants for the vendor presentations, SilverPlatter publications, an OVID Technologies information packet and attendance and registration information. Also included are two VIVA information packets which contain VIVA pamphlets, VIVA fact sheets, agendas, evaluation forms and travel reimbursement information.
    - RFP Committee, February-July 1999 (Box 11, Folder 2)
      Documents and correspondence from the Request for Proposal committee. RFP #M 0182 was a request for a database provider. Documents include schedules of meetings, an official Request for Proposal, attendance information for vendor presentation, journal subscription information, meeting notes and agendas, subscription prices, database provider selection criteria and evaluations, a rough draft of the request for proposal, large note pad pages with meeting notes and VIVA questions and answers.
    - Request for Proposal #M 0127, April 1996-August 1996 (Box 11, Folder 3)
      Request for Proposal #M 0127 for Interlibrary Loan Delivery Service from Federal Express. Also included is the contract between VIVA and FedEx, correspondence, a list of document delivery sites and service codes.
    - Federal Express Response to RFP #M 0127 for Interlibrary Loan Delivery Service, May 1996 (Box 11, Folder 4)
      The official response from FedEx to RFP #M 0127 for Interlibrary Loan delivery service. Material includes a spiral bound FedEx Service Guide, a table of contents, contract details, general information about Federal Express, "Electronic Data Interchange with FedEx", FedEx Datalink, shipping rates, an executive summary, a spiral bound FedEx EDI Invoice and FedEx EDI Remit Implementation Guide and a spiral bound group of "VIVA Topics to be Discussed".
  - Subseries 1.3: VIVA Resource Sharing Committee, July 1994-July 2003
    This subseries contains material generated by the Resource Sharing Committee and its subcommittee the Interlibrary Loan Enhancement Committee, files include ILL Forum information, an article, meeting minutes and correspondence.
    - Resource Sharing Committee-ILL Forum, May-August 2000 (Box 12, Folder 1)
      Information and correspondence generated by the Resources Sharing Committee for the Interlibrary Loan Forum held on July, 14 2000, documents include group information, agendas, comments, notes, registration information and attendance lists, presentation slides and evaluation forms. Also included is a list of ARIEL addresses and VIVA information packets.
    - Resource Sharing Committee, May-July 2001 (Box 12, Folder 2)
      Article from RLG Focus titled "Successful Borrow Direct Model for ILL to Expand in July", meeting minutes and correspondence.
    - ILL Enhancement Committee I, October 1994-March 1999 (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Information and correspondence generated by the ILL Enhancement Committee, documents include ARIEL document delivery protocol information, meeting minutes and agendas as well as presentation slides and information about OCLC Resource Sharing Strategy and FirstSearch.
    - Interlibrary Loan Enhancement Committee II, July 1994-April 1999 (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Information and correspondence generated by the ILL Enhancement Committee, documents include meeting minutes and notes, budget information, ARIEL Document Delivery Protocols and software information, ILL requests through FirstSearch, document delivery RFP Surveys, Virginia Tech Libraries acquisition of electronic information resources guidelines and a list of achievements of the VIVA ILL from 1994 to 1999.
    - Interlibrary Loan Enhancement Committee III, July 1999-June 2000 (Box 12, Folder 5)
      Information and correspondence generated by the ILL Enhancement Committee, documents include A Model for Library Support of Distance Education in the US, committee lists, a list of achievements of the VIVA ILL from 1994 to 1999, institutional borrowing and lending list from 1996 to 1997, meeting minutes, budget information, institutional allocation information, ILL conference information, Universal Resource Sharing Application prod cut description and information, and a proposal Statewide Courier Service.
    - Interlibrary Loan Enhancement Committee, December 1998 and March 1999 (Box 12, Folder 6)
      Two packets of correspondence about the cancelation of the Net Lender reimbursement program as well as an ARIEL software upgrade.
    - ILL Letter, March 1995-February 1996 (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Documents and correspondence generated by the Interlibrary Loan Committee. Material includes contact lists, VIVA listserv and home page information, Ariel guidelines and information, lending information and image processing system specifications.
    - ILL Guidelines, May 1997-August 2000 (Box 12, Folder 8)
      Three versions of ILL guidelines from May of 1997, the proposed guidelines from July 2000, and the approved guidelines from August 2000.
    - ILL Ariel, September 1995-January 2003 (Box 12, Folder 9)
      Documents and correspondence about Ariel including an Ariel survey, Ariel protocols and article about Ariel purchase by Infotrieve.
    - ILL Guidelines, May 1997 (Box 12, Folder 10)
      Eight copies of the May 1997 ILL guidelines.
    - ILL Guidelines, August 1996-February 1998 (Box 12, Folder 11)
      Information and correspondence about allocation of various ILL resources including express mail, memorandums regarding allocations to member schools, delivery allocation memos and lending information.
    - ILL-OCLC Stats, September 1998 (Box 12, Folder 12)
      Statistics and lending information from the Interlibrary Loan and Online Computer Library Center. Two groups of information including VIVA Express Mail Allocations and an ILL summary report.
    - ILL OCLC Stats, November 1998 (Box 12, Folder 13)
      Statistics, correspondence and lending information about Interlibrary Loan including an ILL summary report and a letter to the OCLC.
  - Subseries 1.4: VIVA Outreach Committee, October 1996-July 2001
    This subseries contains material generated by the Outreach Committee. The files includes correspondence, information about the Across the Curriculum forum, meeting agendas, notes and evaluations, presentation slides and contact lists.
    - Outreach Committee-Across the Curriculum, March-July 2001 (Box 13, Folder 1)
      Documents and correspondence generated before and after the VIVA Across the Curriculum Forum on July 27, 2001. The forum addressed the future of literacy efforts in Virginia. Documents include William and Mary promotional publications, travel information, Association of College and Research Libraries publication, registration and attendance information, VIVA information packets, agendas, evaluations and notes from the forum.
    - Outreach Committee-(Formerly Publicity Subcommittee of User Services), October 1996-July 2001 (Box 13, Folder 2)
      Information and correspondence generated by the Outreach Committee and its predecessor the Publicity Committee, documents include contact lists, Publicity Committee 1998 plan, workshop information and presentation slides both hard copy and on a 3 1/2 inch floppy disk.
    - User Group, September-October 1998 (Box 13, Folder 3)
      Information and correspondence from the User Group. Material includes meeting notes, conference invitations, VIVA pamphlet, group status reports, technical issues committee information and member lists, VIVA fact sheets and communication information.
    - User Group, March-November 1999 (Box 13, Folder 4)
      Information and correspondence from the User Group. Material includes publications from the Virginia Libraries Association, meeting notes, a list of vendors attending the user group meeting and communication information.
    - Committee Annual Reports, July 1999-June 2000 (Box 13, Folder 5)